# LUCAS NILSEN

+1 469 638 2568 · bo999seng@gmail.com Stavanger, Norway

# SENIOR FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Senior full-stack engineer with 8 years of experience in designing and developing exceptional customer oriented websites through the use of technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML/CSS and beautiful web design. I am an expert in creating and designing software in a test-driven environment and always keep staying up-to-date on the latest web technologies and seeking an opportunity to improve frontend and increase customer satisfaction.

## STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- JavaScript / Typescript
- React/Redux
- HTML/CSS/SCSS
- JSON, JWT
- WordPress, Shopify
- Python, Django, Java, PHP
- Node.js/Express.js
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL,
- GIT / Agile methodology
- Responsive SPAs
- Figma, UX/UI
- Material UI, Tailwind CSS
- RESTful APIs/ GraphQL
- AWS, Azure, GCP

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Senior Full Stack Developer**

Remote 10/2020 - 06/2023

Accomplishments:

- Developed a scalable and reliable enterprise-level SaaS app for moving companies and customers using React, Node.js, and AWS with RBAC / ABAC access control models, resulting in increased efficiency and customer satisfaction.
- Created and maintained front-end code for customer interface using UI/UX design method, resulting in a 40% increase in customer satisfaction rating based on user feedback.
- Developed interactive real-time data web pages and dashboard UIs using React.js,
  Tailwind CSS, Chart.js, and D3.js, providing users with dynamic and visually appealing data visualization.
- Collaborated with AI engineer to develop several pages, including a Chatbot page, using React and Angular, enhancing user engagement and interaction.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including product managers and designers, to ensure alignment between technical implementation and project goals, resulting in successful delivery of high-quality products.
- Optimized usability of React.js based front-end interface, resulting in a 30% increase in app downloads and improved user retention.

## **Full Stack Developer**

Remote 04/2018 - 09/2020

Accomplishments:

- Developed and maintained efficient Content Delivery Network (CDN) solutions, ensuring optimal performance and delivery of web content.
- Extensive experience in building responsive and user-friendly web applications using React.js, Node.js, and modern front-end frameworks.
- Committed to continuous improvement, staying updated with the latest technologies and industry trends to optimize web applications for maximum speed, scalability, and maintainability.
- Updating and maintaining existing WordPress websites, including content updates, visual enhancements, landing page creation, plugins & widgets.
- Built car renting website under the customer's guideline using React.js and Tailwind CSS.
- Development of cloud hosted web applications and REST APIs using Spring Boot with embedded Tomcat.
- Improve the searchability of several websites by using React.js and Nuxt.js.

# Software Developer

Razer 04/2015 - 03/2018

Accomplishments:

- Developed real-time web-site showing the ratings of staffs' record of performance under the company guidelines using React.js, Chart.js, Bootstrap and so on.
- Joined with web designers to develop web-based integrated searching system for sports commodities of various brands using React.js.
- Proficiency in version control systems like Git and experience with collaborative development workflows have facilitated seamless teamwork and efficient code management.
- Good internship experience in development of single page applications(SPAs) using React.js.
- Developed and maintained user interfaces using React.js, resulting in 30% reduction in development time for new projects.
- Developed and implemented a new front-end interface using React.js, resulting in a 20% increase in page load speed and 17% increase in user engagement.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science in Software Development**

Singapore Institute of Technology • Singapore, 10 Dover Drive 03/2015

# **LANGUAGE**

English(Native Speaker)